well a number of Muslim commentators
declined to take part in this debate as
they didn't want to share a platform
with Majid noaz the author of that piece
who joins me now along with the
political director of The Huffington
Post UK M Hassan and the Muslim
Community activist Mo Ansa you're not
going to sit there and say that you
didn't expect people to be offended when
you tweeted that cartoon well I think
the point I was making was that I wasn't
offended Jeremy and that's on my
personal Twitter timeline I think that's
a very fair point to make but you knew
people would be offended when it went
out there I think some people would be
offended I I can't speak for uh the 2.7
million Muslims that are in the UK nor
can I speak for the 1.5 billion Muslims
across the world the petition that was
set up only gained 1% of this country's
Muslims as signatures so I think it's
fair to say that actually most most
Muslims weren't bothered by it you knew
what you did was offensive to some many
people some some people 1% of this
country's 1 % of this country's Muslims
signed a petition asking for my
deselection in hamson and kilon and
there are 1.5 billion Muslims in the
world that petition was sent out across
the world and only gained 20,000
signatures so I've got to say that
actually it's not a majority some
Muslims were offended but also as a
Muslim I have the right to say I wasn't
offended but actually what are they
offended by they were offended by my
lack of offense but you knew people
would be offended by it some people yes
yeah moan what could you possibly find
to be upset about in that cartoon I
don't know I I didn't find it particular
offensive I think the idea that people
uh found maud's lack of offense
offensive I think is absurd I think it's
palpably ABS said the fact is marud has
been for many years somebody who the
government has used as a community
leader and there somebody who speaks on
behalf and understand Muslim communities
and the important thing is this though
that although I didn't find it
particularly offensive there were always
going to be lots of people who were
going this is a very interesting
distinction you're making you're saying
you didn't find the cartoon offensive
not particularly no not really but you
found the identity of the Tweeter
offensive no I I found the idea that a
potential parliamentary candidate would
take steps which he knew either
knowingly or recklessly was going to
offend lots of people and took that risk
on purpose to offend those people shows
a grave lack of judgment and we hold
that parliamentary candidates he said
precisely the reverse he said it didn't
offend him but linking to a website
which depicts uh profits in bed together
or doing sorry there was no link to I
think people to make that distin there
was no link to any website let's be very
clear what I was attempting to do was
simply speak up on principle for the
minorities within the minorities I.E
those that we saw in this film who feel
they cannot speak because they are
silenced by Voices That claim to speak
in the name of authenticity and
tradition and say you're not allowed to
express a Divergent opinion I think it's
very odd to attack Community leaders who
I I don't actually know too many
Community leaders I know people who work
in their sphere of expertise but to
paint yourself in exactly the guys
you're no I don't represent any said
speaking for those no I'm not I'm saying
I'm trying to speak in repres the
liberal Democrats in Camden where they
elected me of course because I've been
elected by them but so as a liberal
Democrat parliamentary candidate you
knew that tweeting things that might be
seen as gratuitously offensive because
you know what speaking out Against
Racism offends some people speaking out
against homophobia offend some TW to say
I'm offed car is off Against Racism is
it offensive telling people to f off on
your Twitter
timeline I think you've done that too is
it offensive standing for Parliament is
it offensive to you that I tweeted that
cartoon is it offensive to me yes is it
yeah I I do find it offensive I didn't
sign the petition it's interesting you
talk about you find the carto
offensive to be to be honest IM I didn't
sign the petition and I didn't speak out
on that isue pleas what's offensive
about that marid let me speak I'm asking
you had a six minute film can I speak
for a second I don't really care about
the cartoons the cartoons were you
attention seeking being provocative
gratuitous whatever you want my M can I
finish a point my problem mid is that as
as Mo pointed out out and as a lot of
journalists don't point out you have a
long history of upsetting people in the
Muslim Community in a gratuitous manner
that is the real issue that a lot of
people don't recognize offive about the
cartoon oh I find offensive about the
cartoon that in Islam you don't normally
depict the prophet when you do depict
the prophet you don't depict him in bed
with another Prophet you don't depict no
you tweeted a series of you tweeted car
from a series The viewers saw what was
offensive about that one part A wi so if
you tweet one
car on in the same in in the same boat
then I was going to say in the same same
bed I know that would in the sense that
don't object to the cartoon so much as
you object the identity of the tweet no
no no hold on let me be very clear I do
object to the cartoon you know I have a
right to be offended just as Ma has a
right to be offensive he has every right
to tweet that cartoon I defend his right
to do it I think violent threats Etc are
outrageous the issue here is it wasn't a
other Lim PPC tweeting the cartoon that
is true I do have a problem with was
offensive about the cartoon we saw on
our screen tonight that's the only one I
tweeted because that's because that was
one part of a series the only one I
tweeted what did you find offensive I
tweet one page from a book it doesn't
mean I don't represent the rest of the
book come on M course he does come on M
you know perfectly well every single
view of everyone you ever quote what do
you believe in every single view of
everyone you ever qu I'm not here to
debate the cartoon you can debate it
with I care about the carto you clearly
do
because I did find it offensive but I
didn't sign the petition I'm wondering
why I think it was a mistake for people
to go after you over the cartoons I
think they should have gone after you
because your organization for the past
six years has demonized and tried to
discredit mainstream Muslim
organizations and people like the Muslim
Council of
Britain the has given a very long film
here in which he talks about Community
leaders a very point he made about
Community leaders that not really he
said that they don't speak on behal of
Muslims I agree with him no Community
leader I've ever met has claim speak on
behalf of Muslims you think I've got a
right to tweet the cartoon and you agree
with my film what's the debate I agree
with your film because a Ser it's a
series of Straw Men for you to come
along and say that you're this great
denter and reformer speaking out against
mus you did in the film and the reason
new invited you on here is to give that
impression there are people with actual
Grassroots support in the British Muslim
Community who are fighting for gender
rights who are fighting against
extremism who are fighting to have
debates about Majid sadly with great
respect very intelligent guy very arly
doesn't speak for them it has zero
credibility in the Muslim Community is
loed by many Muslims because he goes
around demonizing mainstream Muslim
organizations as supporters of al-Qaeda
he goes around taking government money
and parting the government line on
extremism he goes around promoting
leaders of the edl I I want to bring in
very quiet you are one of these
Community leaders aren't you I don't
know am I I I've I've never professed to
be a community leader I've never bought
a community I've never sold a community
leader I I I won't parent George Gall
but the point is I've never said I'm an
appointed community leader but Maji than
his little group of siop fants they like
painting people in black and white
maid's always had an extremist mentality
and he's never moved away from that and
I think the people of Britain when it
comes election time will be very
concerned about looking towards somebody
who says I am the gatekeeper on what is
acceptable Islam in this country and I
am the one who defines it and yet has
been rejected no not at all I've never
said I am uh and I'm not standing for
Parliament however somebody who's been
rejected by every mainstream Muslim
Civil Society organization and has no
credibility and issues threats and
harass I think people will you want to
make yourself a mar of free speech Mar
having having had a six-minute film you
want to make yourself a mar Free Speech
neither not neither of you have a
problem with my tweeting the cartoon
neither okay so both of you agree that I
have the right to of course and
neither of you have a problem with the
film I do many problems with
filiz as a political candid should you
be offending
large as as a political candidate should
you be potentially offending large part
playing the man and not the ball because
what this film was about was the idea
what this film is about the idea that I
don't sit
here can can I I don't sit here claiming
I'm speaking on beh of anyone my point
is individual individual have the right
to speak on their owners you don't there
are plenty of people who are actually
fighting we don't see a broader range of
Muslim spokesman well Jeremy let me
answer that question for you let's talk
about the role of the media tonight you
have a Muslim debate with three male
Muslim panelists where is the woman
where is the Muslim woman there was a
Muslim woman panelist your producers
dropped her before the show began so
your viewers at home think well there
are no women who can speak within the
British Muslim Community as Sara Khan
rightly said in that film there are
women who've been active within the
Islamic commity for centuries where are
they tonight this is news night's
discussion the media has to take
responsibility for who they choose to
speak on there were two women in that
one of them was an
exim the woman was Dro I think that was
a mistake with the greatest to I think
that was a mistake not have
Muslim volumes
abouted woman would been very happy to
see a more diverse cross-section syst
you ask a really important question
absolutely now you ask a very important
question which media
a main a mainstream media one second a
mainstream media commentator attacked me
this weekend on Twitter because he
believed me to have homophobic views
without actually checking that I've been
standing for for gay rights and working
with the transgender Community for over
15 years now I I wondered had he just
seen my profile picture and he said well
when I complained about it he then
insulted me you can't get away with he
insulted me and then said well you'll
never come on my show again now if
that's how we use and abuse the Muslim
voice in this
just mag's main question who speaks for
Muslims Muslims speak for Muslims and I
wish journalists would understand that
rather than picking people speak on
their behalf thank you all very much
[Music]
thanks