A really common question we're getting in
the chat is about the decision in Canada
to delay the second
dose up to four months.
This was based off a recommendation from
the from NACI, the
National Advisory Committee
for Immunizations.
I think that's the full acronym.
Doctor Sharma can I get your insights on this one?
Sure, so
I mean the first part of it is that
that NACI is, as I said
in my presentation, independent and
it's not part of Health Canada.
I'm getting a lot of emails telling me
that I shouldn't have made that decision.
I didn't, just to be clear.
The Health Canada position
is what's in the product monograph, so
we still from the Health Canada
perspective are saying a 21 day
interval for Pfizer, 28 day for
Moderna and then between four weeks
and 12 weeks for AstraZeneca.
And what NACI does, though is give those
recommendations on how best to use
the vaccines and when they look at
them, they looked
at obviously the clinical trial data.
They looked at real-world data.
We have data from
other countries that have actually used a
longer dosing interval. At the time
that they looked at it,
there was a lot of data around an 8 week
interval between the 1st and
2nd doses of the mRNA vaccines, and of course for
AstraZeneca we already
have that kind of longer
interval in the clinical trials.
They were also looking at
what they knew about vaccines in general.
And we know that when you have
immunity, especially at
these high levels,
that Dr. Gommerman talked about,
they don't just immediately sort of
fall off a cliff all of a sudden.
So we don't know how long they last.
We are getting more information on
how sustained that immune response is,
but we do know that you've
already got a high level.
It's not going to
drop off very quickly, so they
use that along with some modeling,
and then this is the important part,
amd looked at what the supply
situation would be in Canada.
So this is the part that's a bit,
I think, challenging for
people. So they took a look at
what the benefits were
of getting first doses
into as many people as possible
versus sticking to a shorter
interval and potentially then
having more people
having completed vaccination
schedules and
having some people that don't.
And so their recommendation was
that you could go up to and
I'll just say that
again, up to four months
in their opinion,
without compromising the immune response.
They didn't say that you have to, so
I know a lot of places are
automatically giving that second vaccination dose
exactly four months later.
That's not what they said. They were saying, you could,
if it's for, you know,
in your best interest to get more
people vaccinated, you could go
up to four months. Now what they're doing
is that they're also looking at
new data that's come out that's showing
that potentially there might
be some differences
in some of the subgroups, so
people that might have a bit of
a compromised immune
system, such as people that had cancer
and received treatment,
whether or not in the
elderly population so 70 and older,
80 and older.
Maybe their immunity
drops off a bit quicker than
other groups, so they're actually
in the process of looking at
that as well now
and to see if they need to
update that recommendation in any way.
So we've got the Health Canada
sort of strict interpretation of the data,
whether it's clinical trial,
real-world evidence, and then
we have this, like
how do we best use
these vaccines in Canada
to protect us all
in the best ways we can get
you know, back to some state
of normality as quickly
as possible, so that's
where that came from.
But again, I just want to underscore that
it's up to four months and
it's really dependent on availability
of vaccines, and it might change based
on evidence, which you know
is challenging in and of itself,
when we change recommendations.
But just to say that that's
what they're looking at
when they're giving their
recommendations to the provinces
and territories.
Dr Richardson, do you have
anything to add on on that topic,
especially from a
HealthEquity perspective?
Yeah, I really like what you were
just saying Sam about about this
idea of the collective
versus the individual.
We're used to health care
in Canada being entirely focused
on our individual access,
apart from, of course,
the small group of people
who practice public health.
And how can we actually
start to understand that?
Thinking around the collective?
Actually, not only is it a morally
just thing to do because it actually
makes sure that vaccine
access goes to those who
will benefit more from it.
It will help get us
out of the situation that
we're in more quickly.
So how do we actually
ensure that those
postal code regions that
I was talking about that
currently in the heat bath in Toronto
are showing lower access to vaccines and
yet higher rates of COVID?
How do we ensure that
we're getting vaccine there quickly?
I can tell you that the elongated interval
I can see being complex for
some of the outreach work that I'm doing.
When I look at the magnitude
of something called Operation
Remote Immunity, which
involved teams of us flying into
remote First Nations
in the North of Ontario, it was an
unbelievable operation
that would oversee.
It's been done incredibly well
but to look at having now a gap to
actually complete that
after the logistical
infrastructure that
went in, that's going to be complex.
When I look at vaccinating people
in the park for experiencing
homelessness like we
were doing last week here
in Toronto with Anishnawbe Health,
elongating that time is going to be is hard.
We have outreach workers who are going to
meet people three weeks,
four weeks, we can do that. Reminder,
we know where people are
more likely to be, etc.
But when we extend that time for
particularly vulnerable
groups, I do worry a
little bit, so I think that's where when
we start to think from this collective
well being, which actually
will benefit me as well as an
individual because
we will slow the rate of the spread,
increase the likelihood to get to herd immunity.
I think we do need to recognize that
we should be seeing some nuanced
approach to vaccine distribution
and not be angry about that.