FOR THE FIRST TIME IN 20
YEARS THE RACE FOR DISTRICT
ATTORNEY IS BEING CONTESTED.
THREE PEOPLE ARE TRYING TO
REPLACE OUTGOING FIVE TERM
INCUMBENT JAN SCULLY.
WE BEGIN WITH TOM DUHAIN WITH
THE CURRENT BEST -- DEPUTY
DISTRICT ATTORNEY.
LEX THIS IS THE ELECTION PARTY
TONIGHT FOR SCHUBERT, THE
CHOSEN CANDIDATE BY THE OUTGOING
DA OR RECOMMENDED IN THE SHERIFF
AS WELL.
SHE IS A LONGTIME PROSECUTOR IN
THE OFFICE FOR 24 YEARS AND OVER
100 TRIALS.
SHE IS WITH ME NOW.
WONDERING HOW YOU FEEL AFTER
THIS CAMPAIGN AND THE
POSSIBILITY OF FIVE MONTHS MORE?
I AM AS EXCITED
-- EXCITED
ABOUT THE CAMPAIGN.
I AM IN IT TO WIN IT.
HOW WOULD YOU DESCRIBE THE
CAMPAIGN AND DID IT SURPRISE
YOU?
A LOT OF WORK.
I HAVE LIVED IN A DIFFERENT
WORLD OF THE PROSECUTOR FOR 24
YEARS.
WE HAVE BEEN GETTING OUT IN THE
COMMUNITY AND TO HEAR WHAT
THEY'D WANT TO KNOW.
WHAT I
FOUND IS THEY WANT THE
MOST QUALIFIED CANDIDATE.
HOW HAVE YOU REACTED TO THE
FACT THAT YOU ARE ALMOST RUNNING
AGAINST THE BROWN
ADMINISTRATION?
THE ENTIRE ADMINISTRATION MIND
UP BEHIND HER?
HEAVY ENDORSEMENTS FROM LOCAL
LAW ENFORCEMENT.
ALMOST FEELS LIKE STATE VERSUS
LOCAL.
I AM RUNNING THIS CAMPAIGN ON
MY MERITS.
I HAVE NO DOUBT THAT THE
DECISION IS BASED ON MERITS AND
I WIN HANDS DOWN.
WITH ALL DUE RESPECT TO THE
OPPONENT, I HAVE THE SUPPORT OF
NOT JUST LOCAL BUT STATEWIDE
LAW-ENFORCEMENT BECAUSE OF MY
RECORD FOR 24 YEARS IN THE FACT
THAT I HAVE BEEN AN ADVOCATE FOR
PUBLIC SAFETY MY ENTIRE LIFE.
WAS THERE ONE PARTICULAR
ISSUE THAT REALLY DISTINGUISHED
YOURSELF FROM THE OTHER
CANDIDATES?
THE ONE RING IS MY
EXPERIENCE.
PUBLICLY MOST PEOPLE SAVE
REALIGNMENT BECAUSE THAT HAS
BEEN A HOT TOPIC.
I HAVE ALWAYS SAID I BELIEVE IT
IS A VERY HOT TOPIC.
I BELIEVE THERE ARE THINGS WE
NEED TO REMEDY.
THERE HAVE BEEN RECOMMENDATIONS
ON THAT AND I SUPPORT THOSE.
MY RESPONSIBILITY IS TO PROTECT
THE COMMUNITY, AND THAT IS WHAT
MICHAEL WILL BE.
YOUR CAMPAIGN
-- THAT IS WHAT
MY GOAL IS GOING TO BE?
I THINK YOU NEVER
UNDERESTIMATE THE COMMUNITY.
YOU NEVER UNDERESTIMATE MONSANTO
HAS BEEN HERE FOR 58 YEARS, THAT
I GREW UP HERE AND HAVE WORKED
MY TAIL OFF TO GET TO THE POINT
WHERE I AM RIGHT NOW AND BELIEVE
VERY STRONGLY WE HAVE DONE A
TREMENDOUS JOB, THE ENTIRE TEAM
OF REACHING THE VOTERS OF THE
COMMUNITY AND
DEMONSTRATING WHY
I AM THE MOST QUALIFIED
CANDIDATE.
THAT IS THE LATEST HERE.
THE PARTY GETTING UNDERWAY.
REPORTING LIVE, KCRA THREE NEWS.
GOING NOW TO
LIVE AT THE
ELECTION NIGHT HEADQUARTERS OF
DEPUTY ATTORNEY GENERAL CORRELL.
MAGGIE CORRELL EXPECTED TO
ARRIVE HERE IN ABOUT AN HOUR.
VERY POSITIVE AND BOOST ABOUT
WHAT SHE HOPES TO BE A VICTORY
TONIGHT.
SUPPORTERS SETTING UP BALLOONS,
SIGNS, WAITING FOR TIME FOR THE
ELECTION RESULT TO COME IN.
THE DEPUTY ATTORNEY GENERAL SAYS
SHE HAS WHAT IT TAKES TO BE THE
TOP PROSECUTOR.
SHE SAYS HER PRIORITIES, IF
ELECTED TO OFFICE WOULD BE
HELPING LOW LEVEL OFFENDERS GET
BACK INTO SOCIETY AS PART OF
REALIGNMENT AND TACKLING THE
PROBLEM OF SACRAMENTO BECOMING A
SEX TRAFFICKING HAVE.
I AM PROSECUTING HUMAN
TRAFFICKING CASES ON A STATEWIDE
BASIS.
IT IS A GROWING PROBLEM IN
SACRAMENTO AS WELL.
THAT IS ONE ISSUE I WANT TO DO A
BETTER JOB WITH AT THE LOCAL
LEVEL.
AT THE MOST HOPING
SCHUBERT
WILL NOT GET MORE THAN 50% OF
THE VOTES.
PEOPLE GETTING EXCITED TO SEE
THE ELECTION RESULTS TONIGHT.
SPEAKING OF MAGGIE
KRELL,
HAS SHE SHOWN UP YET? SHE IS
EXPECT IT IN ABOUT AN HOUR.
YOU KNOW WE WILL BE COMING
BACK TO YOU WITHIN THE HOUR.
WE KNOW YOU WILL STAY RIGHT
THERE FOR US.
THANK YOU.
ONE
CANDIDATE JUST NEEDS TO GET
50% PLUS ONE VOTE AND THEY WIN.
THERE IS ANOTHER CANDIDATE IN
THIS RACE.
WE ARE TALKING ABOUT TODD
LERAS.
HE WORKED AS A DISTRICT
ATTORNEY.