We've been watching a congressional hearing
erupt into shouting matches. Attorney General
Pam Bondi has been defiant and explosive as
she feels questions from members of the House
Judiciary Committee. And it's happening on
multiple fronts and multiple controversies,
including the Justice Department's
release of the Jeffrey Epstein files.
First, just watch this exchange with
Democratic Congresswoman Primila Jipal.
It is about you taking responsibility for your
Department of Justice and the harm that it has
done to the survivors who are standing right
behind you and are waiting for you to turn to
them and apologize for what your Department of
Justice has done. Members members get to ask
the questions. The witness gets to answer in the
way they want to answer that attorney general.
That's not accurate, Mr. Chairman, because she
doesn't like the answer. So, um, Mr. Mr. Chairman,
I have asked she asked Merritt Garland this I am
reclaiming my time and when I will chairman the
gentle lady get in the gutter for her theatrics.
There was also this moment when Congresswoman
Gyipal asked Jeffrey Epstein survivors who are in
the room to raise their hands if they haven't been
able to meet with the Justice Department. Every
one of them raised their hands. Now, Bondi did
acknowledge in her opening statement the victims
and she said she's deeply sorry for what they've
been through and that the FBI wants to hear from
them. Over the last two hours, it has been very
clear that the attorney general was speaking to an
audience of one. Lots of moments like this. Robert
Mueller found no evidence, none, of foreign
interference in 2016. Have you apologized to
President Trump? Have you apologized to President
Trump? All of you who participated in those
impeachment hearings against Donald Trump, you all
should be apologizing. You sit here and you attack
the president and I am not going to have it.
I'm not going to put up with it. You can let her
filibuster all day long, but not on our watch. Not
on our time. No way. And I told you about that,
Attorney General, before you started. You don't
tell me. Yeah. Oh, I did tell you because we saw
what you did in the Senate. Lawyer. Not even
a lawyer. Within 40 minutes, you asked me a
question. Within 40 minutes, Wexner's name was
added back. Within 40 minutes of me catching
you redhanded. Red hand. There was one redaction
where he's listed as a cocon and we invited you
in. We This guy has Trump derangement syndrome.
He needs to get You're a failed politician.
Okay. I'm joined now uh with our panel. start
with somebody who is the opposite of a washed up
loser lawyer. Thank you. You're welcome. Uh I I I
want to get into, you know, a lot of the specifics
because so much um of sort of what is bubbling
up in in news and controversy goes through the
Justice Department right now across the board,
Epstein files, uh and on and on and on. But I
just want to for a second talk about the tone and
tenor of this hearing. Yes, we saw Pam Bondi do
this the last time she testified. She had, you
know, her list of insults that somebody caught
a a picture of. She knows uh what she feels that
she needs to do so that the president sees her
fighting back. She also wants to deflect on a lot
of these issues where she is in the hot seat. Um,
as somebody who worked at the DOJ, your thoughts
on what we've seen so far? This is a fiasco. Um,
I wish I had a nicer way to put it, but this is
the attorney general of the United States. This is
the top law enforcement official in the country.
This is the same job that was once held by Robert
F. Kennedy, senior, by Elliot Richardson, by
Janet Reno. And there are vital questions that
the American public needs transparency, needs
substantive answers on. Instead, what do we get?
Accusations of Trump derangement syndrome, name
calling, you're a loser, lawyer, this and that.
I mean, coming from the AG of the United States in
the US Senate, did we get any meaningful clarity
on the Epstein investigations, on the Epstein
files? To your point, do the victims feel, MJ,
to what you were saying earlier, like they've
been given any transparency, any clarity on any
of this? Have we learned anything new about what
DOJ is doing to investigate in Minnesota? Have we
learned anything new about the search warrant
in Fulton County? Have we learned anything new
about the fact that dozens of judges across
this country have found that this DOJ lacks
credibility? No. It's been name calling.
It's been amateurish. It's an embarrassment
to the Justice Department. What we're seeing
from Pam Bondi. I mean, plus one, I guess,
in some level, but from the non- lawyer, washed up
or otherwise. Um, I think I'm not some like stuffy
institutionalist. I love a good back and forth
in a hearing. I point to Scott Besson who's had
some really great oneline retorts that he didn't
have to prepare for or have his staff prepare in
a very lengthy book of opposition research before
his hearing. I I think that's a great part of the
game and lawmakers are just as guilty of this as
administration officials and have been from every
single Congress and administration you can think
of. This is farcical and it's embarrassing and it
is also extraordinarily juvenile in the approach.
And to Ellie's point, which I think is important,
as we've seen kind of the congressional role in
the branches of government continue to diminish
year after year after year across several
administrations, but in particular in the last
13 months, like this is an oversight committee of
this agency. There was a moment where a Democratic
lawmaker asked the AG, can you please submit
this document that I'm talking about since you
won't answer questions to the committee? Which the
answer has to be yes. and she said, "I'm not going
to commit to anything because I don't like how
you're answering or asking these questions." Like,
that's it's it's just should not be a plausible
option for a cabinet official, period. And there
are so many important questions which, you know,
there's still a lot of people who are left to ask
questions um including like you said, I mean, one
of the things that we've been talking about a lot
on this show is um the elections coming up. First
of all, the fact that uh the DOJ released the
evidence that they gave to uh allow for and to get
permission for a search warrant in Fulton County,
Georgia. There were a lot of um sort of washed
up to borrow a term from uh Pam Bondi conspiracy
theories that were used and somehow the magistrate
jud judge said yes. There is the lawsuit that DOJ
is involved with uh about 24 states to try
to get really sensitive personal information
uh from them on voters. And so these are
critical issues for the American people and for
the Congress to do their constitutional duty for
oversight and you know sort of owning the libs and
you know showing the conservatives in conservative
media that you're not going to sort of answer
questions of Democrats and even some Republicans.
that does undermine what this is supposed to do.
And you know, look, I mean, to be fair, there are
theatrics on the Democratic side, too. There's
theater, at least bad theater, like not getting
good reviews theater across the board. I think
one of the most striking things to me about these
hearings is they've really devolved over time. And
I wonder if a member just asking a question
plainly without sort of the hyperbole going
into it. I don't think it would change anything
for Pam Bondi in this hearing. But it does get
to the the the whole underlying issue, which is
there was a time where even if it was a Republican
administration, if a Republican witness was
acting that way, the Republican side of the aisle,
at least someone, and not Thomas Massie in this
case, because we know how he and the president
feel about each other, but someone else would
say, you know, as a reminder in the course of
this hearing, and that just is not happening. This
is just a free-for-all. This is for clips. This is
for the president and obviously for the audience
of one that we've been talking about. It's mostly
for the president, right? I mean, the number of
times that she sort of unprompted uh brought up
the president's record, the moment where she was
being asked about Epstein related issues and then
brought up the DAO breaking records and I think it
was a Democratic uh congresswoman who just shouted
into the ether, what does that have to do with
any of this? Uh she clearly is keenly aware of the
audience that she most needs to win over including
on the Epstein stuff which exactly I'm sorry to
interrupt you but we're almost out of time but I
want to just pull something out of you which is
especially on the Epstein stuff because there's a
lot of criticism of her the way that they people
believe conservatives believe she believe she
bungled the beginning of the administration on
this right I mean how many times have we played
the clip of her talking about this so-c calledled
called uh client list and saying it's sitting
on my desk right now. That sort of set off
this entire firestorm of controversies and
she's not been able to shake that off. And
uh you know we've wondered Todd Blanch has
sort of been the main face of the DOJ when
it comes to Epstein issues. Is that because uh she
bungled it so badly initially uh that she couldn't
be trusted to be uh the face of this really
important and politically uh explosive issue.