our economy is going to be phenomenal
next year you can open businesses and
schools if in fact you provide them
the guidance that they need as well as
the money to be able to do it
competing for your vote and tonight
competing for an audience he's pulled
out of almost every international
organization
has your opinion changed on the
importance of mass squaring
nope tonight president donald trump and
vice president joe biden hold
dueling town halls we're taking our
political coverage 360.
the questions voters want answered the
coronavirus response the supreme court
i have not been a fan of pat courtpaki i
think that she's going to make a great
decision i did not tell her what
decision to make
plus we're fact checking claims made
during both town halls our 360 team
coverage on denver 7 news at 10 starts
right now
they were supposed to share a debate
stage instead tonight with less than 20
days until the election president trump
and former vice president joe biden held
town halls same time two different
cities the president miami biden and
philadelphia both answering questions
from voters on
numerous topics with the big focus on
the coronavirus response
tonight is part of our 360 coverage on
these dueling town halls
we have live team coverage denver
seven's eddie gujardo with reaction from
both sides of the aisle first at denver
seven's gary bro
with a look at highlights from both hey
shannon and these two town halls were
quite different both
in length and in tempo president trump's
one hour town
hall was quick it was concise but it
left a lot of questions unanswered
as for former vice president joe biden
his was long and at times his responses
were long-winded they touched on topics
ranging from covid social injustice and
that open supreme court seat in an
unprecedented move
two presidential candidates two town
halls on two networks airing
at the same time do you have any
remaining symptoms from kovitz nothing
whatsoever i'm
great i feel good the president starting
his town hall in miami addressing his
recent bout with kovid
and pictures showing he and several
leaders not wearing masks
days before the president's positive
test everybody's tested
and they're tested often and i also knew
that hey i'm president i have to see
people i can't be
in a basement i can't be in a room i
can't be i have to be out you can see
people with a mask though right i can
but
people with masks are catching it all
the time former vice president joe biden
at his town hall in pennsylvania says
he wants a mask mandate calling out the
president for not wearing his
the words of a president matter
absolutely no matter
whether they're good bad or indifferent
they matter and when a president
doesn't wear a mask or makes fun of
folks like me when i was wearing a mask
for a long time
then as you know people say well it
mustn't be that important
nbc moderator savannah guthrie asks
president trump to clear the air from
the first debate
where he was asked to denounce white
supremacy i denounce
white supremacy and frankly you want to
know something
i denounce antifa and i denounce these
people on the left that are burning down
our cities
vice president biden changing his stance
on a 1994
violent crime bill that many say
incentivized mass incarceration
was it a mistake to support it yes it
was and outlining his new plan to
improve criminal justice
you can ban chokeholds you can but but
beyond that you have to
teach people how to de-escalate
circumstances
de-escalate so instead of anybody coming
at you the first thing you do is shoot
to kill
you shoot them in a leg there's ways you
have to do more background checks in
terms of whether or not
the person coming in passes certain
psychological tests
simultaneously both candidates fielding
questions about the supreme court
vacancy
the president asked why he changed his
stance on filling the seat
before an election you said i think the
senate should wait until the next
president and let the president
pick the whole ball game changed when i
saw the way they treated justice
kavanaugh i have never seen any human
being and i'm not just talking about
supreme court
i have never seen a human being treated
so badly with false accusations
the vote expected to happen days before
the election biden refusing to take a
stance if he will expand
the supreme court don't voters have a
right to know where they do have a right
to know what i stand and i'll have a
right to know where i stand before they
vote
so you'll come out with a clear position
before election day yes gary broad
denver seven we continue our 360
coverage fact checking claims made
during both town halls tonight
focusing on coronavirus and we start
with a claim made by the president that
85 percent of people who wear masks
catch the virus and this is false and a
misunderstanding of the cdc report
released last month
the report looked at more than 150
people who were symptomatic
and tested positive 85 said they had
worn a mask
either always or often over the two week
period before they got sick
that's where the 85 percent comes from
joe biden claimed tonight that one in
five minority businesses have closed
because of copen 19.
this appears to be true and the numbers
actually might even be worse than that
according to a stanford university study
more than one million black owned
businesses in the u.s were open in
february 2020 by april
440 thousand black home businesses had
closed
that's a decrease of more than 40
percent and the president claimed
tonight that original projections for
coronavis deaths in the u.s
would be around 2.2 million people and
this is misleading
the president is referring to a model
published back in march
by imperial college london which
predicted 2.2 million people in the u.s
could die from the virus but only if
no mitigation efforts were in place the
white house coronavirus task force also
said between 1.6 and 2.2 million people
would die if
nothing was done to stop the spread and
joe biden slammed the president for not
helping americans have that extra
hundred dollars a week in supplemental
unemployment benefits which expired in
july
this is false after congressional talks
to extend unemployment benefits
collapsed the president signed an
executive order
to use 44 billion dollars in disaster
aid to provide three hundred dollars a
week
in supplemental benefits and tonight
people on both sides of the aisle are
weighing in
all right our 360 team coverage
continues with andy guajardo
and ada you're hearing from colorado
democrats and republicans tonight
well shannon and some strong feelings
tonight following these dueling town
halls tonight i spoke with colorado
senate president
leroy garcia a democrat garcia tells me
he felt encouraged by joe biden's
performance tonight he says he showed
strength
laid out a vision and has a plan
he said i'm going to be a president for
everyone and that is the second time he
has said that
he means that he understands that he
knows what that means
a president he's going to unite people
now when it came to packing the court
garcia says he supports biden's plan to
wait before making a decision
now we pushed the colorado republican
party for a response tonight but they
just sent us the president's campaign
statement
which states nbc savannah guthrie a joe
biden surrogate is what they called her
now tonight she corrected the president
on several statements including daca and
press for his plan but he didn't
elaborate
only stating that he's working very hard
on a daca plan
now the statement goes on to say
president trump masterfully
handled guthrie's attacks now it goes on
to say again
americans can see that president trump
is leading the country has built the
economy to the best
in the world once and is doing it again
and quite clearly has accomplished more
than 47 months
than biden has and 47 years as a failed
washington politician now in just 19
days voters will have that final
decision
in the meantime president trump is going
to face off with joe biden on the debate
stage
next thursday october 22nd reporting
live in denver addy gujardo
denver seven addie thank you nationwide
in the latest abc news washington post
poll
biden holds a double-digit lead standing
at 53 percent of the president's 41
percent among registered voters
the race is tied among men at 48 percent
while biden is up 59 percent to 36
percent among women
and that is the widest margin among
women for any presidential candidate in
exit polls
dating back to 1976. well colorado
voters are really showing up for this
election
early voter turnout has increased nearly
2400 percent compared to this time in
the 2016 election
secretary of state's office says more
than 300 000 coloradans have already
returned their ballots
so here we are 19 days out from the 2016
election
only about 12 000 coloradans had cast
ballots and of those
300 000 who have already voted this time
around 46
registered democrats 19 registered
republicans
and the arrest unaffiliated all right so
some important
dates and deadlines to keep in mind as
we go forward election day is of course
november 3rd if you want to mail in your
ballot
you need to do that early by october
26th in order for it to arrive
on time for processing you can always
take it
to the thousands of drop boxes that are
located all across our state in fact the
secretary of state's office has a
statewide list
and if you still need to register to
vote you can do that
until 7 pm on election day and colorado
voters can now use a system called
ballot tracks a system that will allow
you to track your ballot from the time
you send it
to the time it's accepted at a
processing facility