fored TV the world is
[Music]
thinking now I will gladly concede
because I think Mr hens is right on this
that there are some forms of religion
that are pathological that damage people
but there's a need I think for a real
discussion about what is pathological
and what is normal about what is the
center and what are the fringes and that
I think also extends to
Mr hitch's analysis of the impact of
religion in general he makes the point
and I think I want to say he is right to
make this point that religion has done
much damage in history I regard that
point as being Beyond contradiction and
it seems to me that every one of us here
this afternoon needs to say that is
right but I think we need also to go
further and begin to explore and the
kind of questions I would like to open
up for discussion would include these
yes religion has done damage but is this
typical or is this a fringe element who
are the normal people who are the
Fanatics and it seems to me there's a
real need to try and make this kind of
adjudication I grant the history is
there that there have been some awful
things done but as Michael Shermer who's
president of the skeptic Society wrote
In the book uh how we believe some years
ago for every one of these atrocities
which must cause all of us deep concern
there are 10,000 unreported acts of
kindness generosity and so forth arising
from religious commitment and trying to
get this balance right seems to me to be
of enormous importance what is The
Fringe what is the center so that's one
point I think I'd like to open up for
further discussion but I'd also like to
try and just make a more General point
and that is that I think World Views in
general whether they are religious
irreligious whatever they are have the
capacity to animate people to the extent
that they feel they must go and do
things which many of us would regard as
morally
reprehensible we see this in the Soviet
Union a rather Grim period in modern
history we find for example lenon having
said basically that there is no higher
authority by which he may be judged
feeling able to I quote uh authorize the
protracted use of brutality against
religious Believers and it seems to me
that we have here an ideology a
worldview which basically is sanctioning
violence in this case anti-religious
violence now I would not argue from that
that this shows that Atheism in general
or atheists in particular are violent
people it's much more about what
movements do to people about the damage
that worldviews can cause when they
begin to take over and begin to really
animate people to want to do things
again look at uh the period under
stallin there are many other examples we
could give of World Views that may well
have begun with great excitement great
enthusiasm a commitment to ideals that
we can all identify with but something
happens and they go wrong the French
Revolution I believe began with an
outburst of energy for Liberty but by
1793 it degenerate into the reign of
terror in which an appeal to Liberty
sanctioned the most Dreadful acts of
violence and many of you will know the
tragic story of Madame Roland who was
brought to the guillotine on trumped up
charges in
1793 and as she was led to the
guillotine she pointed to a Statue of
Liberty in a PL to the Revolution and
said Liberty what crimes are committed
in your
name history I think discloses a complex
judgment here I do not believe that it
simply points to religion as being the
cause of evil I think it points to the
capacity of all worldviews to begin to
do this it's not so much religion or
indeed anti-religion it seems to be
something actually about human nature
itself which means that acts of kindness
can be accompanied by acts of violence
there's something about us I think that
really needs to be addressed there so I
don't think it's a threat forward as
this religion poisons everything I'm not
sure it can do but so can other things
as well the real problem I think is
extremism the kinds of ideologies that
Force violence upon us and those it
seems to me do need to be challenged and
on that I at one with Mr Hitchens but is
it God that's doing this let's move on
and talk about this clearly a very
important question here is how we know
what God is like can you imagine God
saying go and do violence to someone
well I think some could quite easily but
I speak from a specific perspective
namely that of a Christian Theologian
and for Christianity the identity the
nature of God is disclosed in Jesus of
Nazareth he is the image of the
invisible God he is the Fulfillment of
the law and the prophets and when we
look at Jesus of Nazareth we see
something I think that is very very
challenging we have one who refuses to
do violence even in Gethsemane when some
want to raise swords to defend him as
he's about to be betrayed he bids them
put their swords down Jesus does not do
violence but he has violence done to him
and the point I want to make is that
your vision of what God is like has a
profound impact on what you think God is
urging you to do and it seems to me that
if one is a good Christian then one is
going to take the vision of what God is
like and what God wants us to do that we
find disclosed in Jesus with the utmost
seriousness now let me make it
absolutely clear I concede and I may may
well be one of these that there are many
bad Christians around who fail to live
up to this Vision but I want to draw a
clear distinction between some
Christians are bad and Christianity is
bad there is an aspiration and
inspiration and norm and that means one
can challenge those who want in some way
to use violence in the name of God and
of course you can see this impacting on
the way in which people behave in an
episode that happened a year ago here in
the United States you've had
unfortunately in recent days some
shooting incidents and of course what
I'm talking about is the Amish
Schoolhouse killings of October
2006 and many of you will know of these
some of you may have been affected by
them a craze gunman broke into an Amish
Schoolhouse and shot I think it was 10
Amish school girls of whom five
died the Amish as I'm sure you all know
are a very conservative Protestant sect
who wear 17th century clothing who won't
drive cars they use horse buggies and
they also regard the ethical example of
Jesus as absolutely
normative for them there will be no
retribution of any kind the cycle of
violence was broken instantly because
for them Christ ordered them commanded
them to show
forgiveness that's a very important
Point religion or at least in this case
Christianity contains within itself the
capacity for self-criticism this is not
the way God is this is not the way we
should be behaving and I fully concede
there are those who fail to live up to
that but there is a challenge that can
be issued to them why behave like this
when there is the norm before you
authorized as what God would like us to
do so it seems to me there is a very
important point to make there
[Music]
[Laughter]